# **Jamison Johnson**

Waldorf, MD | (732) 447-6302 | jamison.jcjohnson@gmail.com \*Active Top Secret Security Clearance\*

# **Experience Summary:**

IT professional with 13+ years of government support and professional experience in System Administration. Highly proficient with DoD security standards/network security protocols, system hardening, software and hardware troubleshooting, Linux distributions (RHEL, CentOS, & Ubuntu) administration, Windows 10 & Windows Server administration, and creating/maintaining VMware vSphere virtual environments. Great work ethic with a thirst for challenging projects, working with innovative technologies to expand my knowledge, and applying those skills to better support the mission.

#### **Technology Experience:**

- **Operating Systems-** Microsoft Windows Server, Microsoft Windows 10/11, Mac OS X, Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL), CentOS, and Ubuntu.
- Software & Technologies- Windows PowerShell, Group Policy, FreeNAS, PDQ Inventory, PDQ Deploy, Nakivo, Veeam, VMware vSphere (ESXi), Red Hat Ansible, Docker, Podman, ACAS, Nessus, Security Technical Implementation Guides (STIGs)/Security Content Automation Protocol (SCAP), Continuous Monitoring, PKI, Networking, Microsoft Office, Active Directory, Technical Writing, Remedy, Service Now, Windows Remote Assistance, McAfee Endpoint Encryption, Exchange Server, Office 365, SMIME, CAC Cards, RSA Tokens, Citrix Workplace, Virtual Private Network (VPN), Wyse Thin Clients, Switches, Routers, Outlook Web Access, MobileIron MDM, Good Technology MDM, Blackberry UEM MDM, Entrust Registration Authority, Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI), Cisco iOS, Printer Administration, BES Administration, Microsoft System Center Configuration Manager (SCCM), Webex Administration, and IBM BigFix.

#### **Employment History:**

## **Department of Navy - IT Specialist:** 01/2022 – Present

- RHEL administration including image configurations, bash and shell scripting, software installations, user
  administration, data backups, system maintenance, & OS updates/upgrades. The RHEL machines are imaged by a
  kickstart file and STIG scripts which allows all machines to have a uniform build. In addition, the RHEL
  machines are managed together via multiple Ansible playbooks and/or ad-hoc commands.
- Windows administration including Active Directory, Group Policy and PowerShell administration. Group policies were created and maintained with imported DISA STIGs, scanned via the SCAP Tool, and then verified through an Information Assurance (IA) process. Windows patching is configured and completed using PDQ tools.
- Applied Assured Compliance Assessment Solutions (ACAS) scanning solutions and uploaded scan results via Nessus/Tenable. After the ACAS scan was completed, STIG & SCAP scans were also run to stay compliant with DOD DISA standards.
- Created VMware vSphere virtual machines, created backups and restorations, applied server updates, and additional troubleshooting. In addition, I provided, daily monitoring, management, and restoration of virtual machines per customers' needs.
- Implemented and documented processes and procedures for performing system administration activities. I ensured that all newly created documentation was added to the teams SharePoint site for later review.
- Utilized the ServiceNow (SNOW) ticketing system to support customer request and ensured that they were tracked to completion.

### Department of Navy via SimVentions- Senior System Administrator: 01/2021 – 12/2021

- Supported MDM platform MobileIron which was used to configure and support Android mobile devices. Within
  MobileIron the following tasks were required, mobile device configurations/installations, user and device group
  configurations, policy configurations, pushing Google Play and In-house applications, and many more specific
  tasks.
- Ubuntu administration including software installations, user administration, data backups, system maintenance,
   OS updates/upgrades, script writing, and cron job configurations. The activities also included server backups,
   MYSQL database backups, webservice backups, and docker instances backups.
- Provided support for various different technologies. The primary technologies included, Seagate NAS, Synology NAS, Jenkins, Mantis Bug Tracker, Jira, Docker, Linux OS (Ubuntu & CentOS), Windows 10 OS, and Cisco router support.
- Cisco router configuration and support. Various tasked were completed to include the following: Implement Cisco
  AnyConnect configuration settings on the router and the client machines, implement a router configuration
  backup process, edit firewall access rules, and port forwarding settings to improve the security posture of the
  router/network, VLAN configurations, and various other tasks.
- Worked to document processes and procedures for execution of the system administration duties. Ensured that all newly created documentation was added to a shared location on the NAS for later review by the rest of the team.

#### **Department of Navy via SimVentions- System Administrator:** 04/2019 – 07/2021

- Developed and supported over 100 virtual and physical severs and machines within an offline lab environment, utilizing VMWare vSphere within vCenter, working within a team of software developers to provide support to them to address their daily issues.
- Ensured systems are operational for software development and software testing activities. These systems are primary Dell hardware which include laptops, desktops, and rack-mounted servers.
- RHEL administration including software installations, user administration, data backups, system maintenance, & OS updates/upgrades. The RHEL machines are imaged by a kickstart script that allows all machines to have a uniform build.
- Windows administration including Active Directory, Group Policy and PowerShell administration. Group policies were created and maintained with imported DISA STIGs, scanned via the SCAP Tool, and then verified through an Information Assurance (IA) process.
- Created vSphere virtual machines, created backups and restorations, applied server updates, and additional troubleshooting. In addition, I provided, daily monitoring, management, and restoration of virtual machines per customers' needs.
- Documented processes and procedures for performing system administration activities. I ensured that all newly created documentation was added to the teams SharePoint site for later review.

#### **Department of Energy via ActioNet- Technical Lead:** 08/2014 – 04/2019

- Completed quality assurance duties within the Service Now ticketing system. I ensured that the technicians were maintaining and updating their tickets per the OCIO standards.
- Provided technical guidance and assistance for technicians when roadblocks arose. I functioned as a liaison between the Tier-2 and Tier-3 technical groups.
- Created and published SOPs and publish them to the organizations' knowledge base. These documents were used as part of the new hire onboarding process, and allowed technicians to efficiently complete their daily tasks.
- Conducted meetings with a team of technicians to address various issues/concerns. Weekly meetings were conducted to ensure the team was meeting the necessary metrics and Service Level Agreements (SLAs).
- Deployed multiple computers, laptops, monitors, & mobile devices for several incoming and already stationed users as primary or secondary workstations/handheld devices.
- Administrated, monitored, & troubleshoot Active Directory, Entrust, and RSA 7/8 accounts.
- Installed S-MIME Encryption software on several mobile devices and troubleshoot Entrust Encryption computer related issues.
- Installed GOOD Mobile Device Management on all Department of Energy iPhones, iPads & Android devices.
- Investigated network logs & firewalls while monitoring network traffic & malicious website use.
- Provided technical remote assistance in the Citrix Web environment via the Citrix Receiver client.
- Troubleshoot Microsoft Office 365 issues on a day to day basis, primarily through Microsoft Outlook and Lync/Skype of Business, a result from a migration from Microsoft Exchange 2010.
- Engaged and exposed to several different types of scenarios as well as seeing multiple different variations of failures/error messages from Microsoft Outlook and Lync/Skype for Business configured with Office 365, post migration from Microsoft Exchange 2007/2010.

#### Department of Defense via Q-Base- System Administrator: 09/2012 – 06/2013

- Provided troubleshooting and configuration activities for print servers running Windows Server 2003/2008, Active Directory, and Microsoft Exchange
- Attended meetings with management to discuss plans for improvement concerning networking issues
- Tracked all service and trouble tickets involving support to end-users through the utilization of the Remedy ticketing system
- Monitor and maintain server rooms and LAN closets per current policies, including rewiring a specific network closet which cable management needed to be completely removed and replaced.

#### **Department of Energy via ActioNet- Systems Analyst:** 08/2010 – 09/2012

- Managed mobile device administration which entailed troubleshooting blackberry issues and enabling IT policies per current security policies on the server
- Coordinated the Virtual Desktop Infrastructure pilot environment which included Windows 7 and Office 2010
- Provided Entrust Registration Authority services to customers as a trusted agent to collect and verify a PKI subscribers identify
- Performed queue management task as I monitor service requests/incidents as they are reported then assign to the proper groups/individuals
- Provided Macintosh SME which entails configuring and troubleshooting iDevices and Macs
- Coordinated meetings with Cyber Security, PKI, and Network Operation Center
- Researched, resolved, and responded to complex questions received via phone, escalation, and in-person, in order to provide support on electronic services in accordance with current policies
- Acquired and maintained knowledge of relevant product offering, and methods of support delivery, to better handle incidents, projects, or assignments while displaying efficient asset management skills

# **Education | Certifications:**

Virginia State University – Petersburg, VA Bachelor of Science in Computer Information Systems

CompTIA Linux+ Certified Professional HDI Support Center Team Lead CompTIA Security+ Certified Professional CompTIA CASP+ Certified Professional Cyber Security Work Force (CSWF) (August 2016 | Pearson VUE Training Center) (November 2016 | Help Desk Institute) (May 2018 | Prometric Testing Center) (November 2020 | Prometric Testing Center) (January 2022)